# Software Engineer

# CONTACT

+44 7812 163982

dvdjms@hotmail.com

david-james-2b949979

github.com/dvdjms

Edinburgh EH12 5DH

# TECHNICAL SKILLS

# Languages

- **JavaScript**
- **TypeScript**
- Python
- Java
- C#
- HTML & CSS

# Technologies

- Django
- Flask
- **Express**
- Spring
- React
- ASP.net
- **PostgreSQL**
- Styled-Components
- Bootstrap

### Other

- Git & GitHub
- Command Line Tools
- Some AWS Services

# **PROFILE**

Driven software engineer with skills in frontend and backend technologies. With over a decade of experience in accounts and seven years in teaching, I transitioned into tech through CodeClan's Professional Software Development course. My volunteer work with the Scottish Tech Army has provided valuable real-world experience in deploying cloud-based solutions and integrating platforms, allowing me to deliver reliable, scalable technology solutions.

### **TRAINING**

### CodeClan

Sep 2022 to Feb 2023

Comprehensive 16-week programming course. SQA Accredited (Level 8). With over 800 hours of practical coding, individual and groups projects, and expert-led tuition. Included OOP, TDD, UX design, agile methodologies, version control, command line, and pair-programming.

**PROJECTS View Portfolio** 

# WeatherWise

Python/Django/React/SQLite3

• Developed a fully responsive Weather app for a user to search 45,000 cities and get 24 hour and 10-day weather forecasts, taking advantage of APIs from openweathermap.org and met.no. Includes a My Locations dashboard with local time zones. Solo project.

# Recipe Generator

C#/ASP.net/Angular

• Full stack application using C# and ASP.net, with an Angular frontend. Leveraging OpenAI's ChatGPT API, it allows users to select ingredients from a drop-down menu and instantly generate recipes. The generated recipes are displayed in a responsive popup modal. Solo project.

# Learn Scotland

JavaScript/React/Express/Mongodb

• Full stack React application about Scotland allowing a user to interact with quizzes, see scores on a leader board, and post comments. This included a multiple choice, drag & drop, and map location guiz. Group project.

# **EDUCATION**

**MA International Communication**University of Leeds

**BSc (Hons) Psychology** Open University

**BA (Hons) Media Studies**De Montfort University

# **CAREER MOTIVATION**

"Technology is not just my career. It's my passion. I am driven by the desire to create solutions that make a difference."

#### **ACTIVITIES**

Learning new technologies.

Independent travel to Europe, Asia, and North & South America.

Hiking and adventure.

World Cinema.

### **EXPERIENCE**

# Software Developer – Volunteer

Aug 2023 to present

Scottish Tech Army, Edinburgh / Kontroll Solutions, Edinburgh

- Automated project data and location pins on the Scottish Tech Army (STA) website, using APIs from Jira, Google Maps, and postcode.io, improving project visibility and access.
- Developed an AWS Lambda function to populate DynamoDB with Jira project data, enhancing functionality in the STA Volunteer App.
- Trained in AWS Cloud Development Kit (CDK) and deployed solutions.
- Collaborated with Kontroll Solutions to integrate Infraspeak and Unleashed platforms via APIs, streamlining product and stock level synchronization.
- Utilized AWS Services including Lambda, API Gateway, EventBridge, DynamoDB, S3, Secrets Manager, and CDK to deliver cloud-based solutions.

### **Contact Tracer - Test and Protect Scotland**

Oct 2020 to Sep 2022

NHS Lothian, Edinburgh

- Conducted in-depth interviews with Covid-19 positive cases. Identified contacts, high risk situations, public health concerns and infection patterns.
- Used CMS database to record information and communicate with Covid-19 positive cases and their contacts.
- Worked with employers to identify high risk individuals offering public health advice and guidance on best practice.
- Supporting the rest of the team, sharing knowledge, experience, and best practice to support improvements to overall program.

# **English Teacher**

May 2014 to Aug 2021

Whales English, Beijing, China (Online) / Wall Street English, Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam (Onsite) / Various Academies, South Korea (Onsite)

- Educated students of various ages and levels, from elementary to adult learners, in various settings including online, small classes, and social clubs.
- Utilised video software and advanced teaching tools for online classes and conducted trial classes for marketing to new students and parents.
- Self-prepared lessons and interactive activities to target receptive and productive skills, providing individual attention, assessment, and feedback.
- Prepared detailed reports for parents, assessed weekly homework, and provided individualized feedback to support student improvement.
- Demonstrated strong leadership and relationship-building skills, facilitating optimal learning environments.

### **Treasury Accountant**

Jul 2007 to Jan 2014

Avison Young, Birmingham

- Key performer in a highly pressurised target driven environment to reconcile high profile accounts with up to £70 million of monthly transactions.
- Proven abilities in investigating, analysing, and problem solving.
- Resolved complex and challenging problems entailing in-depth investigation.
- Interpreted and presented numerical data accurately Strong Excel.
- Made substantial contributions to improve team efficiency and effectiveness.
- Improved quality and accuracy of reconciliations with advanced Excel skills.
- Collaborated with internal and external stakeholders to deliver results.